Curriculum Vitae

I am Ye Dong (董业 in Chinese), a Ph.D. student at the Institute of Information Engineering, Chinese Academy of Sciences (CAS) and School of Cyber Security, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences (UCAS), under *Prof. Xiaojun Chen.* I got my bachelor's degree from the School of Computer Science and Technology, Shandong University, and had been an exchange student at the School of Computer, Beijing Institute of Technology. I had been one Research Assistant at NETWORK & INFORMATION SECURITY LAB under *Prof. Qiuliang Xu & Prof. Han Jiang*.

Personal Data

Email 19950512dy@gmail.com.

Citizenship Shandong, China.

Web https://ye-d.github.io/.

Research Topics

Secure Multiparty Computation

Familiar Secret Sharing, Oblivious Transfer, Garbled Circuits.

Basic Homomorphic Encryption.

Security and Privacy of Machine (Deep) Learning

Familiar MPC-Private ML/DL, Secure Aggregation of Federated Learning.

Basic Byzantine-Robustness, Attacks & Privacy Leakages, Quantization

Technologies.

Education

Sep. 2018 - Present PhD in Cyber Security, (expect to graduate in June. 2023),

Institute of Information Engineering, Chinese Academy of Sciences & School of Cyber Security, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences,

Beijing, China.

Sep. 2014 – June. 2018 Bachelor in Computer Science and Technology, Shandong University,

Jinan, Shandong.

Sep. 2015 – June. 2016 Exchange Student, School of Computer, Beijing Institute of Technology,

Beijing, China.

Theses

PhD Thesis (Institute of Information Engineering, CAS; Ongoing)

Supervisors Xiaojuen Chen

Bachelor Thesis (Shandong University; June. 2018)

Title Privacy-Preservation and Mining of Zcash

Supervisor Han Jiang

Previous Experience

Teaching & Work

Summer. 2021 & 2022 **Teaching Assistant**, *University of CAS*, Beijing, China.

Big Data Security and Privacy-Preserving

Mar. 2022 - Sep. 2022 External Consulting, Primihub, Beijing, China.

Consultancy services on Multi-Party Computation and related technologies

Oct. 2016 – June. 2018 Research Assistant, Network and Information Security Lab, Shandong

University, Jinan, China.

Supervisor Prof. Qiulaing Xu & Prof. Han Jiang

Community Service

Dec. 2022 Reviewer, CVPR.

Reviewer for the IEEE / CVF Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Conference $2023\,$

Sep. 2022 Reviewer, CASE.

Reviewer for the 7th International Conference on Computer Science and Application Engineering 2022

Sep. 2021 Reviewer, IEEE Systems Journal.

Reviewer for the IEEE Systems Journal 2021

Jul. 2020 External Reviewer, FCS.

External Reviewer for the International Conference on Frontiers in Cyber Security 2020

Others

Jul. 2022 **Attendance**, *DAC*, Hybrid Conference, Co-author.

Attend the 59th Design Automation Conference

May. 2021 Attendance, CCF-YEF, Shenyang, China.

Sep. 2020 Attendance, ESORICS, Online Conference, Co-author.

Attend the 25th European Symposium on Research in Computer Security

Languages

Chinese Native

English Fluent

Computer Skills

OS Linux, Windows, Ma- Typography LaTeX, Microsoft Of-

cOX fice, Markdown

Scientific Octave, Pytorch, Ten- Programming Python, C, C++, sorflow Shell

Open-Source Projects

CryptoFL Cryptographically Secure Aggregation for Federated Learning.

https://github.com/Ye-D/CryptoFL

METEOR Meteor: Improved Secure 3-Party Neural Network Inference with Reducing Online Communication Costs.

https://github.com/Ye-D/Meteor

Awesome Lists

PPML-Resource **Privacy-Preserving-Machine-Learning-Resources** .

https://github.com/Ye-D/PPML-Resource

APC Awesome Privacy Computing .

https://github.com/primihub/Awesome-Privacy-Computing

Awards

2020 & 2021 Merit Student Award, University of CAS.

2020 **Institute Excellence Award**, Institute of Information Engineering, CAS.

2016 **Exchange Campus Scholarship**, Shandong University.

2015 **School Scholarship**, Beijing Institute of Technology.

2014 – 2018 **School Scholarships**, *Shandong University*, Multiple Times.

Talks

Oct. 2021 FLOD: Oblivious Defender for Private Byzantine-Robust Federated Learning with Dishonest-Majority, ESORICS 2021, Virtual Conference.

Dec. 2019 Privacy-Preserving Distributed Machine Learning Based on Secret Sharing, *ICICS* 2019, Beijing, China.

Publications

- 1. Ye Dong, Xiaojun Chen, Xiangfu Song, and Kaiyun Li. FLEXBNN: Fast private binary neural network inference with flexible bit-width. *Accepted to TIFS, CORE Rank A*, CCF Rank A*, 2023.
- Ye Dong, Xiaojun Chen, Weizhan Jing, Kaiyun Li, and Weiping Wang. METEOR: Improved secure 3-party neural network inference with reducing online communication costs. Cryptology ePrint Archive, Accepted to WWW, CORE Rank A*, CCF Rank A, 2023.
- 3. Liyan Shen, Ye Dong, Binxing Fang, Jinqiao Shi, Xuebin Wang, Shengli Pan, and Ruisheng Shi. Abnn²: secure two-party arbitrary-bitwidth quantized neural network predictions. In *Proceedings of the 59th ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference, CORE Rank A, CCF Rank A*, pages 361–366, 2022.
- 4. Yiran Liu, Ye Dong, Hao Wang, Han Jiang, and Qiuliang Xu. Distributed

- fog computing and federated learning enabled secure aggregation for iot devices. *IEEE Internet of Things Journal*, 2022.
- Zhendong Zhao, Xiaojun Chen, Yuexin Xuan, Ye Dong, Dakui Wang, and Kaitai Liang. Defeat: Deep hidden feature backdoor attacks by imperceptible perturbation and latent representation constraints. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, CORE Rank A*, CCF Rank A, pages 15213–15222, 2022.
- Ye Dong, Xiaojun Chen, Kaiyun Li, Dakui Wang, and Shuai Zeng. Flod: Oblivious defender for private byzantine-robust federated learning with dishonest-majority. In *European Symposium on Research in Computer Security, CORE Rank A, CCF Rank B*, pages 497–518. Springer, 2021.
- 7. Kaiyun Li, Xiaojun Chen, Ye Dong, Peng Zhang, Dakui Wang, and Shuai Zen. Efficient byzantine-resilient stochastic gradient descent. *FL-Workshop@IJCAI*, 2021.
- 8. Dong Ye, Hou Wei, Chen Xiaojun, and Zeng Shuai. Efficient and secure federated learning based on secret sharing and gradients selection. *Journal of Computer Research and Development*, 57(10):2241, 2020.
- Liyan Shen, Xiaojun Chen, Jinqiao Shi, Ye Dong, and Binxing Fang. An efficient 3-party framework for privacy-preserving neural network inference.
 In *European Symposium on Research in Computer Security, CORE Rank A, CCF Rank B*, pages 419–439. Springer, 2020.
- 10. Ye Dong, Xiaojun Chen, Liyan Shen, and Dakui Wang. Eastfly: Efficient and secure ternary federated learning. *Computers & Security, CORE Rank B, CCF Rank B*, 94:101824, 2020.
- 11. Ye Dong, Xiaojun Chen, Liyan Shen, and Dakui Wang. Privacy-preserving distributed machine learning based on secret sharing. In *Information and Communications Security: 21st International Conference, ICICS 2019, Beijing, China, December 15–17, 2019, Revised Selected Papers 21, CORE Rank B, CCF Rank C*, pages 684–702. Springer, 2020.
- 12. Liyan Shen, Xiaojun Chen, Dakui Wang, Binxing Fang, and Ye Dong. Efficient and private set intersection of human genomes. In 2018 IEEE International Conference on Bioinformatics and Biomedicine (BIBM), short paper, pages 761–764. IEEE, 2018.